

DATA SCIENCE AND ANALYTICS LEADER

Chicago, IL, USA

■ 616.706.3471 | ■ jim.kloet@gmail.com | 🖸 jimtheflash | 🛅 jimkloet | 💆 @jimkloet

Summary

Hi, I'm Jim! I'm passionate about helping people and organizations make better decisions. So far, I've accomplished this by building and leading teams of talented data professionals across several industries, e-comm, consumer goods, healthcare, and academic research. Let's talk!

Experience

Slam Dunk Betting Services

Chicago, IL, USA

2024 - Present

CO-OWNER

• We build machine learning tools and alerts for NBA props with +EV, distributed via Discord subscriptions

• Developed real-time scraping tools to grab the latest odds from sportsbooks

Reverb Chicago, IL, USA

MANAGER, Product Analytics & Data Science

2021 - 2024

- I built a team of 7 data scientists and analysts supporting data science and analytics needs for product and eng teams, and senior leadership
- We developed and supported tooling for running and analyzing 120-150 controlled A/B tests per year
- We built and supported tools for gear recommendations, price predictions, and matching listings to entries in a music gear database

ABC Supply Co. Chicago, IL, US

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST, IT Data Science

2019 - 2021

- · Led data science initiatives across several domains, including workforce management, associate retention, security, and e-comm
- Developed project plans and supervise students and interns on capstone projects and hackathons with university partners
- · Created and disseminated standards and best practices in data visualization and code management with R packages

Nielsen Chicago, IL, USA

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST, Data Science as a Service

2019 - 2019

- Developed containerized pipelines to ETL data to and from AWS environments using python for a CPG client
- · Generated recommendations for optimal nationwide pricing and promotion strategies, delivered via Tableau dashboard

Mattersight Chicago, IL, USA

DIRECTOR OF INSIGHTS & ANALYTICS, SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

2015 - 2019

- Led team of data scientists and analysts responsible for reporting and ad-hoc analysis for all subscription clients
- Automated analytic tools in R and SQL to scale implementation of best practices in statistical analyses and data visualization
- Led presentations for clients and internal audiences on development and use cases for predictive analytics, esp. predictive CX measures

RotoViz rotoviz.com

DIRECTOR OF VISUAL APPLICATIONS, CONTRIBUTING WRITER

2013 - 2019

- · Develop web applications to give users insights into performance of professional sports teams and players
- Train new writers and developers in data science and data visualization methods using R

Northwestern University Evanston, IL, USA

Translational Research Fellow, Doctoral Candidate, Research Technician, Communication Sciences & Disorders

2009 - 2015

- · Designed, executed, and analyzed experiments to investigate language and learning in the brain using fMRI and rTMS
- Presented experimental results at conferences, invited lectures, and in peer-reviewed publications

Skills

Programming R, SQL, Python, git, Matlab, LTEX

Big Data Azure, DataBricks, Hive, Impala, Hue, Beeline

Education

Northwestern University

MA, PHD (ALL BUT DISSERTATION), Cognitive Science, Communication Sciences & Disorders

201.

Evanston, IL, USA

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

BA, Psychology

MARCH 22, 2024 JIM KLOET RESUME